<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Retailing brokers Commune concilium tentum in camera Guihalde Ciuitatis Londini, nono die Aprilis, anno regni dominæ nostræ Elizabethæ, Dei gratia Angliæ, Franciæ, &amp; Hiberniæ Reginæ, fidei defensoris &amp;c. Tricesimo septimo. Coram Iohanne Spencer, Maiore Ciuitatis Londini, &amp; Aldermannis eiusdem Ciuitatis, ac maiore parte Communiariorum Ciuitatis pr[æ]dictæ de Communi Concilio eiusdem Ciuitatis existentium.</title>
            <title>Acts &amp; Orders. 1595-04-09</title>
            <author>City of London (England). Court of Common Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1595</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 16 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 3 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A06228</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 16715</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S107719</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99843415</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99843415</idno>
            <idno type="VID">8147</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A06228)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 8147)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 476:05)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Retailing brokers Commune concilium tentum in camera Guihalde Ciuitatis Londini, nono die Aprilis, anno regni dominæ nostræ Elizabethæ, Dei gratia Angliæ, Franciæ, &amp; Hiberniæ Reginæ, fidei defensoris &amp;c. Tricesimo septimo. Coram Iohanne Spencer, Maiore Ciuitatis Londini, &amp; Aldermannis eiusdem Ciuitatis, ac maiore parte Communiariorum Ciuitatis pr[æ]dictæ de Communi Concilio eiusdem Ciuitatis existentium.</title>
                  <title>Acts &amp; Orders. 1595-04-09</title>
                  <author>City of London (England). Court of Common Council.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>3 sheets   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Imprinted by [J. Windet for] Iohn VVolfe, printer to the honourable Cittie of London,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1595]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Imprint from colophon; printer's name from STC.</note>
                  <note>An act for reforming abuses by retailing brokers.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Retail trade --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Receiving stolen goods --  England --  London --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-09</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="document">
            <pb facs="tcp:8147:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>English royal blazon</figDesc>
               </figure> 
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>blazon of the City of London</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>Retailing Brokers,</head>
            <opener>
               <dateline>Commune Concilium tentum in Camera Guihalde Ciuitatis Londini, <date>nono die Aprilis, Anno Regni Dominae noſtrae Elizabethae, Deigratia An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gliae, Franciae, &amp; Hiberniae Reginae, fidei defenſoris &amp;c. Triceſimo ſeptimo.</date> Coram Iohanne Spencer, Maiore Ciuitatis Londini, &amp; Aldermannis eiuſdem Ciuitatis, ac maiore parte Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>muniariorum Ciuitatis praedictae de Communi Concilio eiuſdem Ciuitatis exiſtentium.</dateline>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">F</seg>Oraſmuch as diuers parcels of Plate of her Maieſties, and of other perſons of honor and credite, haue of late yeares beene ſtolne, and her Highneſſe Armes or honorable Eſchochions, and the Eſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>chochions of others, owners, therevppon being engrauen, haue beene defaced and blemiſhed: and many Iewels, Chaines, and Bracelets, and ſuch like thinges of Golde and Pearle, haue beene imbezelled from diuers honorable perſons and others. And for that within this Cittie and the Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties of the ſame, there be very many Burgularies, Robberies, and Fellonies, dayly committed and done, many vile and notable Coozenages and deceites practiſed and put in vre, and many hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſes alſo infected with the Plague, by reaſon that diuers perſons, called Retayling Broggers, Brokers or Huckſters, and others, ſuch as vſe to buy olde Apparell, Houſeholdſtuffe, Bedding, Bookes, Endes, and Remnants of Silkes and Veluets, or of Lin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nen and Wollen cloth, or ſuch like, to ſell agayne, inhabiting within the ſame Cittie and the Liberties thereof: vnder pretence of lawfull and iuſticiable contracting, doe often, very ſecretely for vnhoneſt lucre, and that moſt ordinarily, vppon the Sabbaoth dayes, Feſtiuall dayes, and other Holy dayes, whereon no markets ought to bee kept, nor bargaines, contractes, or ſales to bee made, receiue, buy, and take to pawne, at the handes of baſe, ſhifting, and ſuſpected perſons, for very low prices, or ſmall ſoms of money, diuers Plate, Iewels, Goods, Wares, Merchandiſes, Apparell, Bookes, and Bedding, Remnantes and Endes of Silkes, Veluets, and of Linnen and Wollen cloth, and other ſuch like thinges, whereof the greateſt part are ſtolne, ſome part gotten from the owners by Coozenage and ſleight, and ſome newly brought out of houſes infected with the Plague, takinge thereof billes of ſale. And the ſame doe preſently ſell againe, &amp; tranſact ſometimes to perſons vnknowne, ſometimes to French and Dutch Brokers, who ſecretely conuay and make tranſportation thereof beyond the Seas, ſo that the right proprietors and true owners, by coulour of ſuch pretended ſales and ſecrete tranſportation, are not onely fruſtrated and depriued of all ordinary meanes for recouery or reſtitution of their ſaide goods, but alſo the fellons and malefactors, are thereby for the moſt part encou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>raged and their offences cloaked and concealed. For due reformation whereof bee it enacted by the Lord Mayor, Aldermen, and Commons in this Common Councell aſſembled, and by the authoritie of the ſame, that from hencefoorth, no Retaylinge Brogger, Broker, or Huckſter, nor any other perſon or perſons whatſoeuer, within this Cittie or the Liberties thereof, ſhall vp<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on any Sabbaoth day, Feſtiuall day, or other Holy day, being not open market dayes, receiue, buy, or take to pawne, or ſell a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Plate, Iewels, Goods, Wares, Merchandizes, Houſeholdſtuffe, Apparell, Bookes, Bedding, or any Endes or Remnantes of Silkes, Veluets, or of Linnen, or Wollen cloth, or any ſuch like thing. And that for euer hereafter there ſhalbe kept and written within this Cittie and Liberties thereof, true and perfect Regiſter bookes, by fower ſuch honeſt and ſufficient perſons, being Free-men of this Cittie, as from time to time, by the Court of Lord Mayor and Aldermen of the ſaide Cittie, ſhalbe to that purpoſe nominated appoynted and ſworne, and at ſuch certayne places, as by the ſame Court ſhalbe likewiſe appoynted, Wherein they ſhall truely and particularly enter, aſwell the names and ſurnames of euery ſuch Retayling Brogger, Broker, and Huckſter, and of euery other perſon, with the place of his and their dwelling, who ſhall receiue, buy, or take to pawne any Plate, Iewels, Goods, Wares, Merchandizes, Houſeholdſtuffe, Apparell, Bookes, Bedding, Endes, and Remnauntes of Silkes, Veluets, or of Linnen or Wollen cloth, or ſuch like. And of euery ſuch perſon and perſons, with the place of his and
<pb facs="tcp:8147:2"/>their dwelling, who ſhall at any time hereafter, deliuer, ſell, or impawne the ſame, As alſo a true, plaine, and particular note, and certayne deſcription of all and euery ſuch thinge or thinges, ſo deliuered, ſolde, or layde to Pawne, to any ſuch Retay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ling Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter, or to any other perſon or perſons, with the true and iuſt prices and ſummes of money, for which the ſame are or ſhalbe ſo deliuered, ſolde, or impawned: To the intent that any perſon from whome any ſuch thinges haue bene vnlawfully taken or conuaighed, may make ſearch in the ſaide Regiſter bookes for the ſame. And bee it further ena<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cted that no ſuch Retayling Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter, nor other perſon whatſoeuer, within the ſame Cittie, or Liberties thereof, ſhall at any time hereafter directly or indirectly by himſelfe, or colourably by any other, buy, receiue, or take to Pawne, or to keepe as pledge or pawne, or cauſe or ſuffer any other to his vſe, to buy, receiue, or take to pawne, or to keepe as a pledge or pawne, any Plate, Iewels, Goods, Wares, Merchandizes, Apparell, Houſeholdſtuffe, Bookes, Beddinge, or any Endes of Silkes, Veluets, or of Linnen or Wollen cloth, or any other ſuch like thinges whatſoeuer, before ſuch time as ſuch Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter, or other perſon or perſons, haue brought and preſented to the Regiſters or ſuch as ſhalbe appointed to kepe the ſaid Regiſter Bookes, and at ſuch place or places, where ſuch Regiſter Bookes ſhall be appointed to be kept as aforeſaid, or to one of them, all ſuch partie and parties, who ſhall offer any ſuch Plate, Iewels, Goods, Wares, Merchandiſes, Appa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rell, Houſeholdſtuffe, Bookes, Beddinge, Remnantes, or Endes of Silkes, Veluet, Linnen, or Wollen cloth, or any ſuch like thing, to ſale, keepe, or pawne, and haue plainely and openly ſhewed to the ſaid Regiſters, or to ſome of them, who ſhalbe ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pointed to keepe the ſame bookes, All ſuch thing or thinges ſo offered to pawne or ſale, without any alteration of the nature, colour or quallitie thereof. Nor before ſuch time as he haue cauſed true note and entry to be regiſtred in ſome one of the ſayde Regiſter bookes, aſwell of the names and ſurnames, and dwelling place or places of the perſons which ſhall ſo buy, receiue, or take the ſame to pawne, or to kepe, and of the partie or parties, who ſhall ſo offer to ſale or pawne or to be kept, any ſuch thing as aforeſaide. As alſo a true plaine and perfect entrie or note, deſcribinge the nature, colour, and qualitie of the thinge or thinges ſo offered to ſale, or pawne, or to be kept, and of the true prices, and ſummes of money, for which the ſame are to bee ſolde or impawned, And whether the ſame bee abſolutely and <hi>bona fide</hi> ſolde, impawned, or left to be kept, And if the ſame ſhalbe impawned, or left to be kept, then, for what time of Redemption, and when to be redeliuered. And if the ſame ſhall be abſolutely and <hi>bona fide</hi> ſolde, That then it ſhall not be lawfull vnto, or for any ſuch Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter, or other per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſon or perſons whatſoeuer to make ſale, put away, or alter the nature, colour, or qualitie of the thinge or thinges ſo abſolutely and <hi>bona fide</hi> ſolde as aforeſaide, within the ſpace of ſeauen dayes next after the buying thereof. To the intent that if it haue bene ſtolne, the right proprietors and owners, may freely view and ſee the ſame, For euery which entrie, euery ſuch Broggar, Broker, and Huckſter and other perſon or perſons, ſhall pay to the Keeper of the ſaide Regiſter booke, one halfe penny, if the thing or thinges ſo entred, be to be ſold, kept or impawned for fiue ſhillinges or vnder. And if the ſame bee to bee ſolde, kept, or impawned, for more then fiue ſhillinges, then he or they ſhall pay for euery ſuch entrie, one penny, and no more. And bee it further enacted that no ſuch Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter, or other perſon or perſons whatſoeuer, within the ſaid Cittie or Li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>berties thereof, after notice or warninge giuen to hym or them by any of the ſaide Regiſters, of any Plate, Iewels, Goods, Wares, Merchandizes, or any other thinges, affirmed to be ſtolne, ſhall buy, receiue, or take the ſame to pawne, or to keepe, or cauſe the ſame to bee bought, receiued, or taken to pawne, or to bee kept, directly or indirectly, or alter any propertie thereof, to defraude her Maieſtie, or the right owners thereof, but ſhall make ſtay of any ſuch thing or things ſo offered to ſale, or pawne, or to be kept, And ſhall cauſe the partie or parties ſo offering the ſame to ſale, or pawne, or to bee kept, to bee apprehended and brought before ſome of her Maieſties Iuſtices of Peace within the ſame Cittie, to bee examined concerning the ſame Fellonie ſuppoſed. And at euery ſuch apprehenſion ſhall giue notice &amp; knowledge to the ſame Regiſter, who left the ſaid warning aſwell of the partie ſo taken, as of ſuch goods by him or them ſo offered to be ſolde, impawned or kept, To the intent that the right owner, or owners of the ſame may bee aduertiſed of the ſaide Regiſter, of the partie and goods, ſo taken and apprehended. And if any ſuch Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter, or other perſon whatſoeuer, within the ſayde Cittie or Liberties thereof, ſhall haue bought, receiued, or taken to pawne, or to keepe, any ſuch Plate, Iewels, Goods, Wares, Merchandizes, or other things as aforeſaid, being ſtolne, before any ſuch notice or warning thereof giuen to him as aforeſaide. Then preſently vpon ſuch no<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tice
<pb facs="tcp:8147:3"/>or warning, he ſhall come to one of the ſaide Regiſters, and truely declare to him how, when, and of whome hee bought or tooke the ſame to pawne, or to keepe. And whether he haue made ſale thereof againe or not. And if hee haue not made for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer ſale thereof before warning or notice giuen, that ſuch thinge is ſtolne, as aforeſaide, Then hee ſhall not make ſale or alter the forme, colour, nature, or propertie thereof, within the ſpace of ſeauen dayes following, To the intent the right proprietors may freely view and ſee the thinges ſuppoſed to be ſtolne. And be it further enacted by the authority aforeſaid: that the Kee<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers of the ſaide Regiſter bookes, nor any of them, ſhall not exacte or demaunde of any perſon or perſons, for any ſearch to bee made in the ſaide Regiſter bookes, aboue the ſomme of one penny, except the parties comming to make ſearch, doe deſire that ſearch may bee made for longer time then one moneth before. And then the ſaide parties ſhall pay for euery ſuch ſearch, two pence and not aboue, neither ſhall demaund or exact for entring or regiſtring of any note, aboue the value and rate aboue decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red, vpon paine to forfeite their ſaide offices or places. And be it enacted by the authority aforeſaide, That no ſuch Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter or other perſon whatſoeuer, ſhall conceale, chaunge, or falſely reporte the names or ſurnames, or dwellinge places of ſuch perſon or perſons, that ſhall ſell, impawne, or leaue to keepe, any ſuch thinges as aforeſaide, whereby any falſe entrie ſhall or may bee made into the ſaide Regiſter bookes, or any entrie omitted contrary to the intent of this Act, And that no ſuch Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter, nor any other perſon whatſoeuer, ſhall buy, receiue, or take to pawne, or to keepe, or ſell, any ſuch Plate, Iewels, Goods, Wares, Merchandizes, Apparell, Bookes, Bedding, or other ſuch like thinges, which hath come out of any houſe infected with the plague within the ſpace of three monethes before ſuch ſale, receiuing, or takinge to pawne, or to keepe. Nor ſhall put to ſale any ſuch Plate, Iewels, Goods, Wares, Merchandizes, Apparell, Beddinge, Bookes, Houſeholdſtuffe, or ſuch like, before he haue hanged or laide open the ſame vppon the walles, or open ſtalles, in open ſtrecte, or other open place, to the view of Paſſengers, by the ſpace of ſeauen dayes at the leaſt. And that no ſuch Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter, nor any other perſon or perſons whatſoeuer, ſhall tranſport beyond the Seas any Plate, Iewels, Goods, Wares, Merchandizes, old Apparell, or houſeholdſtuffe whatſoeuer, before he haue cauſed true entrie therof to be made into the ſayd Regiſter <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 chunk">
                  <desc>…</desc>
               </gap>es, or one of them as aforeſayd, and before <gap reason="illegible" extent="1 word">
                  <desc>〈◊〉</desc>
               </gap> of the ſaid Officers, or Keepers of the ſayd Regiſter bookes aforeſayd, haue taken view thereof. And furthermore that n<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter, or other perſon whatſoeuer, within the ſayd Cittie and Liberties thereof, ſhall ſell, lend, hyre out, or giue away, any pawne, pledge, or gage, before the ſame be forfeyted for want or fault of redempcion. And bee it further enacted by the ſame authoritie, That if any ſuch Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter, or other perſon whatſoeuer, ſhall offende or make default in any article, clauſe, pointe, or matter, contrary to the true meaning of this Act, Then euery ſuch Broggar, Broker, or Huckſter, or other perſon ſo offending, or making de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fault, ſhall forfeite for euery ſuch offence or default, the ſumme of fiue poundes of lawfull mony of England. The one halfe ther<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>of to be to the vſe and behoofe of the Mayor, Comminalty, and Citizens of London, the other halfe to the vſe of ſuch Officers or perſons as ſhalbe appointed by the Court of Lord Mayor and Aldermen for the keeping of the ſaid Regiſter booke or bookes as aforeſayd. And ſhall alſo forfeite to the party grieued, the full value of the thing ſo bought, receyued, or taken to pawne, or to keepe, and concealed or vntruely entered. All which forfeytures or penalties, ſhall bee recouered by Action of Debt, Bill, Plainte, or Information, in any of the Queenes Maieſties Courtes holden within the ſayd Citty. Prouided alwayes that this Act nor any thing therein contayned, ſhall not extende to prohibite or reſtrayne any ſuch Broker, or Huckſter, or any other perſon, But that they may lawfully and openly buy any ſuch Goods, Wares, Merchandizes, or other thinges aforeſayde, at a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny Out-roope within this Citty or Liberties thereof, as freely as they might before the making of this Acte. And that thys Act ſhall not extende to the preiudice of any Merchant vſing the trade of Merchandize, nor to the preiudice of any Broker, be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tweene Merchant and Merchant, except in ſuch caſe, where any ſuch Broker, ſhall happen to deale as a Retayling Broker or Huckſter, as aforeſayd. Any thing in this Act to the contrary notwithſtanding. And be it further enacted that the former Act made heretofore at the Common Councell here holden the nine and twentieth day of May, in the fixe and thirtieth yeare of the Queenes Maieſtyes raigne, for reformation of the abuſes for Brokers ſhall from hencefoorth be vtterly repealed and voide.</p>
            <closer>God ſaue the Queene.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Imprinted by Iohn VVolfe, Printer to the honourable Cittie of London. 1595.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
